http://www.mpimet.mpg.de/en/privacy-policy

Navigation
DE EN
Institute Recommendations for handling the corona virus Corona Task ForceGeneral information on COVID-19FAQsOur AimOrganisationStaffVisitor Information International OfficeHotel ListIT User AccountsRegulations for Use of IT FacilitiesPassword policy and account unlockPosterLibrary and Information ServicesContactOpportunitiesEqual Opportunities Mentoring and career advancementReconciliation of work and familyScience OverviewThe Atmosphere in the Earth System Department MembersWorking Groups Global Circulation and Climate Group MembersPublicationsPrecipitating Convection Group MembersResearchPublicationsStratospheric Forcing and Climate Group membersVolcanoesClimate EngineeringPublicationsTropical Cloud Observation ResearchBarbados Cloud Observatory HALO Group MembersPublicationsWave Driven Circulations Group membersDrivers of tropical circulation Group MembersPublicationsCloud-wave coupling Group membersPublicationsField Studies FESSTVaLEUREC4ANARVALBlogs BarbadosShips Workshops Ringberg Workshops Ringberg 2014 Ringberg 2015 Ringberg 2018ISSIEarthCARE Fact SheetRelevant PublicationsAES Seminar ArchiveThe Land in the Earth System Department MembersWorking Groups Director's Research Group Group MembersPublicationsClimate-Biogeosphere Interaction Group MembersPublicationsLecturesWorkshop-Material CMIP6 landcover change emission dataLanduse change emission dataLUCID-CMIP5 EMBRACE-CMIP5Vegetation Cover BenchmarkingCLIMBER PublicationsGlobal Vegetation Modeling Group MembersPublicationsJSBACH PublicationsBoundary Layer Measurements and Modeling Group MembersPublicationsLand use in the Earth system Group MembersPublicationsTopics for studentsPublicationsLES RetreatsThe Ocean in the Earth System Department MembersScientific Working Groups Director's Research Group Group MembersPublicationsAMCP Group membersPublicationsOcean Statistics Group MembersPublicationsOcean Biogeochemistry ResearchGroup MembersPrevious Group MembersPublicationsPublications 1995 to 2003 of former MPIfM group OceanOcean Physics Group MembersFormer membersProjectsPublicationsDecadal Climate Predictions - MiKlip Group MembersPublicationsSea Ice in the Earth System Group MembersPublicationsObservations, Analysis and Synthesis Group MembersPublicationsPublicationsIndependent Research Groups Cloud-wave couplingEnvironmental Modeling Group membersProjectsPublicationsIMPRS-ESM Research areas Atmosphere PhD candidatesPhD topicsPublicationsLand PhD candidatesPhD topicsPublicationsOcean PhD candidatesPhD topicsPublicationsHuman Dimension PhD candidatesPhD topicsPublicationsAcademic programme Advisory Panel systemCurriculum SeminarsCourses RetreatsOpportunitiesOur people PhD candidatesPhD representativesAdvisorsLecturersExecutive CommitteeAlumniOffice staffAdministration Executive CommitteeIMPRS-ESM office Our servicesPhD at the Universität HamburgHow to apply Potential supervisorsReference lettersFAQs - Frequent questionsModeling with ICON Ruby and SapphireICON Configurations ICON-Ruby (ICON-ESM)ICON-Sapphire (ICON-LEM)ICON-AICON-L/JSBACHICON-OScientific computingCode availabilityObservationsProjects Integrated ActivitiesExternal ProjectsArchivePartnershipsPublications JAMES Special Section 2JAMES Special SectionReports on Earth System ScienceArchiveGood scientific practiceCommunication CommunicationOur TeamNewsFocus onSeminars Seminar OrganisationSeminar ArchiveMultimedia Figures Structure of the AtmosphereEarthsystem SchemaBig Marine Conveyer BeltClimate SystemGreenhouse EffectWatercyclePosters Our InstituteClimate SystemOcean CirculationClimate fluctuationsVolcanismGreenhouse EffectMilestonesVideo ClipsVisualisationsAudioClimate FAQClimate linksInformation material
MPI Website /Privacy policy
Data protection informationThe Max-Planck-Gesellschaft zur Förderung der Wissenschaften e.V. (MPG) takes the protection of your personal data very seriously. We process personal data gathered when visiting our websites in compliance with applicable data protection legislation. We neither publish your data nor transmit them to third parties on an unauthorized basis.
In the following section, we explain which data we record when you visit one of our websites, and exactly how they are utilized:
A.    General information1.    Scope of data processingAs a matter of principle, we gather and utilize users' personal data only to the extent required to ensure the functioning of our website and of our contents and services. The gathering and utilization of our users' personal data normally occurs after users have granted their consent. An exception occurs where data processing is legally permitted.
2.    Legal basis of data processingTo the extent that permission of the affected individual is obtained for the processing of personal data, Article 6 (1) lit. a of the EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) serves as the legal basis.
In the processing of personal data to fulfil a contract whose contractual party is the individual affected, Article 6 (1) lit. b GDPR serves as the legal basis. This also applies to processing required to implement pre-contractual measures.
If processing is required to safeguard the justified interest of the MPG or a third party and the interests, basic rights and basic freedoms of the affected individual do not outweigh the first-mentioned interest, Article 6 (1) lit. f GDPR serves as the basis for such processing.
3.    Data deletion and storage durationThe affected individual's personal data are deleted or blocked as soon as the purpose of the storage ceases to apply. Storage can also occur if provided for by European or national legislators in EU regulations, acts or other legislation to which the MPG is subject. A blocking or deletion of data then occurs only if a storage period prescribed by one of the aforementioned norms expires, unless a necessity exists in relation to the further storage of the data for the arrangement of a contract or the fulfilment of a contract.
4.    Contact details of the individuals responsibleThe entity responsible in the meaning of the General Data Protection Regulation and other national data protection acts as well as other data protection legislation is the
Max-Planck-Gesellschaft zur Förderung der Wissenschaften e.V. (MPG)
Hofgartenstrasse 8
D-80539 Munich
Telephone: +49 (89) 2108-0
Contact form: https://www.mpg.de/contact/requestsInternet:
https://www.mpg.de 5.    Data Protection Manager's contact detailsThe Data Protection Manager at the entity responsible is
Heidi Schuster
Hofgartenstrasse 8
D-80539 Munich
Telephone: +49 (89) 2108-1554
E-mail: datenschutz@we dont want spammpg.deB.    Provision of the website and creation of log filesEach time you visit our website, our service and applications automatically record data and information from the computer system of the visiting computer.
The following data are gathered temporarily:Your IP addressDate and time of your access to the websiteAddress of the page visitedAddress of the previously visited website (referrer)Name and version of your browser/operating system (if transmitted)These data are stored in our systems' log files. These data are not stored together with the user's other personal data.
The legal basis for the temporary saving of data and log files is Article 6 (1) lit. f GDPR. Storage occurs in log files in order to ensure the website's functionality. The data also help us optimize the websites, eliminate malfunctions and ensure our IT system security. Our justified interest in data processing pursuant to Article 6 (1) lit. f GDPR also lies in such purposes.
The data are deleted as soon as they are no longer required to achieve the purpose for which they were gathered. If data are gathered for the provision of the website, this is the case if the respective visit is ended. In the instance that data are stored in log files, this is the case after seven days at the latest. Storage above and beyond this period is possible. In this case, the users' IP addresses are deleted or removed so they can no longer be allocated to the visiting client.
The recording of data for the provision of the website and the storage of data in log files is essential to operate the website. As a consequence, users do not have an option to revoke such data recording.
C.    Web analysisFor the statistical data recording of utilization behaviour, we deploy the Matomo web analysis program (formerly: Piwik), which utilizes cookies and JavaScript to collect various information on your computer and transmit it to us automatically. Each time you visit our websites, our system records the following data and information from the visiting computer's computer system:IP address, anonymized by shorteningTwo cookies to differentiate different visitors (pk_id and pk_sess)Previously visited URL (referrer), if communicated by the browserName and version of the operating systemName, version and language setting of the browserAdditionally, if JavaScript is activated:URLs visited on this websiteTimes at which pages are visitedType of HTML queriesScreen resolution and colour depthFormats and techniques supported by the browser (e.g. cookies, Java, Flash, PDF, WindowsMedia, QuickTime, RealPlayer, Director, SilverLight, Google Gears)Data are stored and evaluated exclusively on a central server operated by MPG. Along with the central www.mpg.de website, it is utilized by most Max Planck institutes and many of the project websites allocated to MPG.
The legal basis for the processing of users' personal data is Article 6 (1) lit. f GDPR. Processing of users' personal data enables us to analyze our users' utilization behaviour. The evaluation of the data we obtain enables us to aggregate information about the utilization of our websites' individual components. This helps us constantly improve our websites and their user-friendliness. Our justified interest in data processing pursuant to Article 6 (1) lit. f GDPR also lies in such purposes. The anonymization of the IP address sufficiently takes into consideration users' interest in the protection of their personal data.
The data are deleted after the formation of the conclusive annual sums for access statistics.
It goes that saying that you are able to revoke data gathering. You have the following independent possibilities to revoke data recording by the central server:
1.            In your browser, activate the do-not-track or do-not-follow settings. If these settings are active, our central server will not store any data relating to you. Important: The do-not-track instruction generally applies only for the device and browser in which you activate the setting. If you utilize several devices/browsers, you will need to separately activate do-not-track in all relevant locations.
2.            Utilize our opt-out function. Click the following selection box https://www.mpg.de/privacy-policy/data-collection-opt-out in order to stop data recording or to reactivate it. If the selection box is deactivated, our central server will not store any data about you. Important: For the opt-out, we have to store a special recognition cookie in your browser. If you delete it or utilize another PC/browser, you will need to revoke data recording again on this page.
These data are not stored together with the user's other personal data.
D.   Utilization of cookiesOur website utilizes cookies. Cookies are text files stored in the
Internet browser or by the Internet browser on the user's computer
system. If a user visits a website, a cookie can be stored on the user's
operating system. This cookie contains a sequence of characters
enabling the browser to be clearly identified when visiting the website
again.
We deploy cookies to make our website more user-friendly. Some
elements of our website also technically require the identification of
the visiting browser after a change of page. The following data are
saved and transmitted in the cookies:Language settings (localization) of the browser: session cookie i18nextSession
data (click path, pages visited, current language, and, where relevant,
error messages for forms: session cookie MPG_session_rBoth cookies are deleted when the session is closed.
The legal basis for personal data processing while utilizing cookies
is Article 6 (1) lit. f GDPR. The purpose of utilizing technically
necessary cookies is to simplify the utilization of websites for users.
Some of our website's functions cannot be offered without the
utilization of cookies. For these, it is necessary that the browser can
also be re-identified following a change of page. We require cookies for
the following applications:Transferring the browser's language setting: automatic selection of the homepage and spellingNoting of form data entered: terms and entries in the contact form utilized in searches within the website (section F)User data gathered by technically necessary cookies are not utilized
to prepare user profiles. Our justified interest in personal data
processing pursuant to Article 6 (1) lit. f GDPR also lies in such
purposes.
Cookies are stored on the user's computer, which transmits them to
our site. For this reason, you, as the user, also have full control over
the utilization of cookies. You can deactivate or restrict the
transmission of cookies through changing your Internet browser settings.
Cookies that have already been saved can be deleted at any time. This
can also occur automatically. If cookies for our website are
deactivated, you may find not all of the website's functions can
continue to be utilized in full.
In addition, we also utilize cookies on our website to enable users'
utilization behaviour to be analyzed. For more information on this
topic, please refer to the information provided under C.
E.    Contact formA contact form is available on our website for the purposes of making
contact electronically. If a user opts for this, the data entered in
the data entry form are transmitted to us, and we save the data. These
are generally your email address, family name and first name. We inform
you about the specific processing of the data and we obtain your consent
as part of the utilization procedure. Reference is also made to this
data protection statement. The data are utilized exclusively to process
the conversation.
The Google reCaptcha function is utilized in order to avoid improper
use of the form. reCaptcha serves to prevent mass machine use of the
contact form by inserting image-based questions which only a human being
can answer. reCaptcha is an embedded JavaScript, which establishes a
connection to the provider's servers when the contact form is accessed.
The provider thereby at least receives information that you have visited
the contact form as well as, potentially, other information that your
web browser and the device you are utilizing discloses. You can obtain
information about the data processing at the provider through a
reference on the contact form.
The legal basis for the processing of data when utilizing the contact
form is the user's consent pursuant to Article 6 (1) lit. a GDPR. We
employ the processing of personal data from the data entry form solely
to process the initiation of the contact. The data are deleted as soon
as they are no longer required for the purpose for which they were
gathered. This occurs if the respective conversation with the user ends
or if the user's issue has been processed conclusively. The conversation
has ended if the circumstances suggest that the respective matter has
been clarified conclusively. At any time, users can notify the listed
contact partners that they are revoking their consent to the processing
of personal data.
The legal basis for the processing of users' personal data by
reCaptcha is Article 6 (1) lit. f GDPR. reCaptcha is utilized
exclusively to ensure the functionality of the contact form and to
prevent improper use. Our justified interest in data processing pursuant
to Article 6 (1) lit. f GDPR lies in such purposes. Utilization is
essential to operate the contact form. As a consequence, users do not
have an option to revoke such data recording.
F.   RegistrationOn our websites, we offer users the option to register, entailing the
entry of personal data in a data entry form. We generally gather your
email address, family name and first name. We inform you about the
specific processing of the data and we obtain your consent as part of
the registration procedure. Reference is also made to this data
protection statement.
The legal basis for the processing of data is the user's consent
pursuant to Article 6 (1) lit. a GDPR. If registration serves to fulfil a
contract whose contractual party is the user or to implement
pre-contractual measures, the additional legal basis for the processing
of data is Article 6 (1) lit. b GDPR. Registering the user is necessary
to provide certain contents and services on our website or to fulfil a
contract with the user or to implement pre-contractual measures. The
data are deleted as soon as they are no longer required to achieve the
purpose for which they were gathered. This is the case for data gathered
during the registration process if registration is cancelled or
modified on our websites. For the registration process to fulfil a
contract or to implement pre-contractual measures, this is the case if
the data are no longer required to fulfil the contract. After the
contract ends, it may be necessary to continue to store the contractual
partner's personal data in order to fulfil contractual or statutory
obligations.
As a user, you can cancel the registration at any time. You can have
the data saved in connection with yourself modified at any time. The
procedure is described in more detail in the specific registration
procedure. If the data are required to fulfil a contract or to implement
pre-contractual measures, early deletion of the data is possible only
to the extent that no contractual or statutory obligations prevent such
deletion.
G.   Data transmissionThe management and storage of your personal information occurs in the case of selected servicesContact form (section E)Registration form (section F)Your personal data will only be conveyed to state institutions and
authorities in legally essential cases or for criminal prosecution based
on attacks on our network infrastructure. The data are not transmitted
to third parties for other purposes.
H.     Rights of individuals affectedAs an individual whose personal data are gathered as part of the
aforementioned services, you have, in principle, the following rights,
to the extent that no legal exceptions are applicable in individual
cases:Information (Article 15 GDPR)Correction (Article 16 GDPR)Deletion (Article 17 (1) GDPR)Restriction of processing (Article 18 GDPR)Data transmission (Article 20 GDPR)Revocation of processing (Article 21 GDPR)Revocation of consent (Article 7 (3) GDPR)Right
to complain to the regulator (Article 77 GDPR). For the MPG, this is
the Bavarian Data Protection Authority (BayLDA), Postbox 606, 91511
Ansbach.
